[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a public sector insurance company?",
    "option1": "United India Insurance Company Limited",
    "option2": "The New India Assurance Company Limited",
    "option3": "SBI Life Insurance",
    "option4": "General Insurance Corporation of India",
    "answer": "SBI Life Insurance"
  },
  {
    "question": "As per the recommendations of the National Statistical Commission, the Base Year of the GDP Series in India was revised from 2004-05 to ______ with effect from January 2015.",
    "option1": "2011-12",
    "option2": "2013-14",
    "option3": "2005-06",
    "option4": "2009-10",
    "answer": "2011-12"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which of the following sectors of the economy do Basel III norms belong?",
    "option1": "Banking ",
    "option2": "Capital market",
    "option3": "Automobile",
    "option4": "Aviation",
    "answer": "Banking "
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Indian finance minister was India’s delegate to the World Monetary Conference at Bretton Woods in 1944?",
    "option1": "KC Neogy",
    "option2": "CD Deshmukh",
    "option3": "John Mathai",
    "option4": "RK Shanmukham Chetty",
    "answer": "RK Shanmukham Chetty"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Reserve Bank of India introduced a comprehensive regulatory framework for NBFC-MFI on __________.",
    "option1": "10-Dec-15",
    "option2": "02-Dec-11",
    "option3": "8-Dec-2013",
    "option4": "05-Dec-12",
    "answer": "02-Dec-11"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ______ was nationalised in the year 1949.",
    "option1": "Union Bank of India",
    "option2": "Reserve Bank of India",
    "option3": "Imperial Bank of India",
    "option4": "Central Bank of India",
    "answer": "Reserve Bank of India"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known as the father of Blue Revolution in India?",
    "option1": "Verghese Kurien",
    "option2": "Sam Pitroda",
    "option3": "Hiralal Chaudhuri",
    "option4": "M.S. Swaminathan",
    "answer": "Hiralal Chaudhuri"
  },
  {
    "question": "Labour Intensive Technique would get chosen in a–",
    "option1": "Labour Surplus Economy",
    "option2": "Capital Surplus Economy",
    "option3": "Developed Economy",
    "option4": "Developing Economy",
    "answer": "Labour Surplus Economy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Surplus earned by a factor other thus land in the short period is referred as –",
    "option1": "Economic Rent",
    "option2": "Net Rent",
    "option3": "Quasi-Rent",
    "option4": "Super-Normal Rent",
    "answer": "Quasi-Rent"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Relationship between rate of interest and consumption level was firstly estimated by–",
    "option1": "Amartya Sen",
    "option2": "Milton Freedman",
    "option3": "Irwing Fischer",
    "option4": "James Duezan Berry",
    "answer": "Milton Freedman"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to worldwide great depression, ‘New Deal’ was declared by?",
    "option1": "Abhraham Lincon",
    "option2": "Benzamin Frankllin",
    "option3": "J.F. Kennedy",
    "option4": "Roozwelt",
    "answer": "Roozwelt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rent is a cost paid for–",
    "option1": "Land",
    "option2": "Restaurant",
    "option3": "Building",
    "option4": "Factory",
    "answer": "Land"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Production of a commodity mostly through the natural process is an activity of–",
    "option1": "Primary Sector",
    "option2": "Secondary Sector",
    "option3": "Tertiary Sector",
    "option4": "Technology Sector",
    "answer": "Primary Sector"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Social Accounting system in India is classified into–",
    "option1": "Assets, Liabilities and Debt Position",
    "option2": "Public sector, Private Sector and Joint Sector",
    "option3": "Income, Product and Expenditure",
    "option4": "Enterprise, Households and Government",
    "answer": "Income, Product and Expenditure"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ is the value of dismantle material of the built-up property after useful period.",
    "option1": "Scrap Value",
    "option2": "Salvage Value",
    "option3": "Market Value",
    "option4": "Book Value",
    "answer": "Scrap Value"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ is the estimated resale value of an asset at the end of its useful life.",
    "option1": "Scrap Value",
    "option2": "Salvage Value",
    "option3": "Market Value",
    "option4": "Book Value",
    "answer": "Salvage Value"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fund containing money set aside or saved to pay off a debt or bond is called-",
    "option1": "Sinking Fund",
    "option2": "Mutual Fund",
    "option3": "Saving Fund",
    "option4": "None of the above",
    "answer": "Sinking Fund"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gradual Loss in the Value of Property due to its use, wear and Tear, Obsolescence is called-",
    "option1": "Appreciation",
    "option2": "Depreciation",
    "option3": "Net Worth",
    "option4": "Total Loss",
    "answer": "Depreciation"
  },
  {
    "question": "A voluntary arrangement between two or more parties that is enforceable by law as a binding legal agreement is known as __________",
    "option1": "Job",
    "option2": "Loan",
    "option3": "Contract",
    "option4": "Mutual fund",
    "answer": "Contract"
  },
  {
    "question": "A tender is advertised in ______",
    "option1": "newspapers",
    "option2": "business environment",
    "option3": "domestic markets",
    "option4": "sellers",
    "answer": "newspapers"
  }
]
